<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-23T11:33:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">UCD Blog | Isabella Huang</title><subtitle>Blog for CSCI 5839, written by Isabella Huang.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Reading Assignment 8: Visual Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/22/reading8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Assignment 8: Visual Design" /><published>2019-10-22T15:10:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-10-22T15:10:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/22/reading8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/22/reading8.html">&lt;p&gt;Organization and Visual Structure (Mullet and Sano)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the discussion regarding balance, it is interesting that they juxtapose 
pieces of two different time periods and languages, 
as we know that style and design evolve over time and culture (figure 111).
Furthermore, the “assymetrically” balanced piece can be seen as balanced,
if one considers the rule of thirds.
Indeed, the focus is set at an intersection of thirds, using the principle
of lines and flow to make the piece engaging and attractive.
One could not argue that the contemporary piece is balanced without appealing
to white spce, which seems to be only tacitly referenced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arranging Elements (Duarte)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Organization and Visual Structure (Mullet and Sano)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Assignment 7: Usability</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/18/reading7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Assignment 7: Usability" /><published>2019-10-18T12:52:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-10-18T12:52:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/18/reading7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/18/reading7.html">&lt;p&gt;My everyday task will be making coffee (because a mathematician’s job
is turning coffee into theorems).
I do this every morning as a coffee nerd does:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;first: weighing out the beans (requires a scale)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;second: grinding the beans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;third: heating the water (requires a kettle)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fourth: mixing grounds with water (I’ll skip the intricacies of this “step”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In weighing out the beans, the gulf of execution is small.
It is pretty clear through simple trial and error that when you put something
on the scale, the scale display will change accordingly.
However, the gulf of evaluation is large. 
Depending on the quality of the scale, there will be a lag between when
things are set on scale and when the scale updates.
This lag contributes to the ability to answer the question of whether one has
put enough beans on the scale, i.e. whether one has executed this 
step fully!
Moreover, the buttons of the particular scale I use lack tactile feedback,
thereby increasing the gulf of evaluation.
It is immediately unclear whether I have truly pressed the button to tare the scale or 
to turn off the scale – which turns out to be the same button.
I have to wait for at least 2 seconds to determine whether I have “done the thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these issues with the scale, I would refer to the heuristic of “visibility
of system status”. 
Indeed, much of the problems identified ask the question of
when the system “understood” the input of the user – 
in other words, when the status of the system updated with respect to 
user input.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My everyday task will be making coffee (because a mathematician’s job is turning coffee into theorems). I do this every morning as a coffee nerd does:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Assignment 6: Prototyping</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/04/reading6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Assignment 6: Prototyping" /><published>2019-10-04T12:52:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-10-04T12:52:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/04/reading6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/10/04/reading6.html">&lt;p&gt;It seems that Li et al’s Topiary tool would be especially apt for use in our project, 
given that we are seeking to develop an app that puts location of self and others 
at the forefront.
It would afford us a Wizard of Oz tool to simulate location updates during user testing.
We could use data collected through the cultural probes (i.e. hand-drawn maps) 
to develop the back-end of Topiary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the emotional mapping part of our project, prototyping could look many different ways.
I could envision us sketching different layouts and faces for emotion updating, also informed by our cultural probes (i.e. emotion chart).
To capture the interactivity and updating of emotions, we could add on to the Topiary system to include alerts and updates.
Wizard of Oz designs would be best to simulate other users’ interactions that the tester is informed about.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It seems that Li et al’s Topiary tool would be especially apt for use in our project, given that we are seeking to develop an app that puts location of self and others at the forefront. It would afford us a Wizard of Oz tool to simulate location updates during user testing. We could use data collected through the cultural probes (i.e. hand-drawn maps) to develop the back-end of Topiary.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 6: Sketching</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/30/sketching.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 6: Sketching" /><published>2019-09-30T18:52:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-30T18:52:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/30/sketching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/30/sketching.html">&lt;p&gt;Location sharing for a meetup app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drew the interface I envisioned for a user selecting where on the map their home is. One would be able to drag and zoom through gestures and click on the home icon to select.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/locationapp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;locationapp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding on the Apple TV:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I envisioned two different ways one could code on an Apple TV. 
The first involved using Scratch and control through movement of the blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second involved using predictive text and a QWERTY keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/codeappletv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;coding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Location sharing for a meetup app:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Assignment 5: Sketching</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/25/reading5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Assignment 5: Sketching" /><published>2019-09-25T15:52:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-25T15:52:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/25/reading5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/25/reading5.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/storyboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;storyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 5: Interview</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/23/interview.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 5: Interview" /><published>2019-09-23T10:52:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-23T10:52:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/23/interview</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/23/interview.html">&lt;p&gt;In class, we practiced interviewing through an exercise about hobbies.
I was being interviewed, and because I was not comfortable with my interviewer,
I decided to make up a persona to impersonate.
My persona’s hobby was riding a Razor scooter.
Understandably, this activity was quite foreign to my interviewer, and it took him a while to understand what my hobby entailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions that were most helpful in elucidating this hobby, from the perspective
of the interviewee, included ones of the type:
“Describe to me one time that you (did this activity).”
For the interviewee, this allows them to speak specifically.
Otherwise, the natural mode is to generalize, and through generalizations, it is
hard to elicit a clear picture.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In class, we practiced interviewing through an exercise about hobbies. I was being interviewed, and because I was not comfortable with my interviewer, I decided to make up a persona to impersonate. My persona’s hobby was riding a Razor scooter. Understandably, this activity was quite foreign to my interviewer, and it took him a while to understand what my hobby entailed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 5: Cultural Probe</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/23/cultural-probe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 5: Cultural Probe" /><published>2019-09-23T10:52:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-23T10:52:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/23/cultural-probe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/23/cultural-probe.html">&lt;p&gt;We designed two cultural probes for our project. 
Our project has two different dimensions: physical location and emotional location.
For the matter of physical location integrated with community, we thought asking our participants
to draw their own understanding of their physical community through a map
would elucidate their relationships with physical space and landmarks.
Furthermore, asking them to envision both their day and their friends’ days
as integrated within the sketch would conduct an exercise of situating
their experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In re the second matter of emotional locations,
we designed an emotional mapping exercise, in which participants are asked to
locate their emotions within a non-descriptive chart.
Furthermore, they are asked to name the feeling and face and potentially
describe their emotions in detail.
Such an exercise has the aim of allowing the participants the space and time
to better understand their emotional geography throughout a day.
Moreover, it gives a better sense of what emotions are experienced and how
people relate to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/culturalprobe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cultural probe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We designed two cultural probes for our project. Our project has two different dimensions: physical location and emotional location. For the matter of physical location integrated with community, we thought asking our participants to draw their own understanding of their physical community through a map would elucidate their relationships with physical space and landmarks. Furthermore, asking them to envision both their day and their friends’ days as integrated within the sketch would conduct an exercise of situating their experiences.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Assignment 4: Interviews</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/18/reading4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Assignment 4: Interviews" /><published>2019-09-18T12:13:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-18T12:13:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/18/reading4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/18/reading4.html">&lt;p&gt;*Kane et al: At times avuncular and cantakerous, with the reflexes of a mongoose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the introduction of the study, the authors note that the population interviewed for the study is small by nature of the method and thus poses a limitation for the conclusions drawn. 
However, they also note that this population itself is scarce – an incidence rate of ALS reported to be about one in 50,000. 
Moreover, the interviewees are predominantly male, which also reflects the patterns of the disease.
This tension is apparent in any work pursued in the context of underrepresented populations
where the question of how to best represent a community is fraught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is only slightly ironic that the method used to understand this population is through a medium (conversation) that they struggle with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Bennett et al: How teens with visual impairments take, edit, and share photos on social media&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After noticing many of my JEDI-minded friends on social media including descriptions of their image posts (especially on meme pages),
my interest was piqued with regards to how we can best make accessible the media we have deemed as a community to be note-worthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple act of going through one’s personal social media feed or profile is deeply revealing,
not just of one’s habits and interests but also of how that medium is situated within one’s identity and how it shapes one’s identity.
Such a tool – social media profile – allows one to tell their own curated story and serves as a powerful tool for understanding.
Interviewing through such an act seems to be deeply revealing and could be fruitful for other forms of research.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Kane et al: At times avuncular and cantakerous, with the reflexes of a mongoose</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 4: Personas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/16/personas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 4: Personas" /><published>2019-09-16T13:21:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-16T13:21:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/16/personas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/16/personas.html">&lt;p&gt;On Monday as a small group, we discussed personas with respect to Google’s Cardboard VR headset.
We approached the task through reverse-engineering, brainstorming different use cases that we knew of or that we could envision.
We did generate use cases that were pretty traditional for virtual reality in general, such as video games and sharing of experiences. 
However, we sought to focus on those that were particularly suited for Google Cardboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the use cases was in the classroom, for education.
We envisioned students using VR in the classroom in lessons that would benefit from different means of visualization, most notably in geometry classes.
The compelling reason to use a cardboard headset would be cost.
That is, cardboard is a cheap material and thus not too consequential in the hands of clumsy elementary school students.
Furthermore, to ensure equal participation, all students need access to a VR headset, requiring at least a handful of sets per classroom and thus a need to keep per item costs low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another use case we thought of was in the context of professional training.
While on the surface, training in virtual reality is simply more engaging than sitting through a seminar, 
there are compelling reasons that could commit an employer to utilize VR.
Similar to a motivation to using VR in – say – chemistry classrooms, the compelling rationale for utilizing VR in professional training revolves around safety.
Similar to the case in classrooms, scale is an important consideration in using cheaper media.
Furthermore, the goal is to come away with some form of learning.
However, the trainee will most likely have outgrown the clumsiness of childhood and will be interacting less in an exploratory manner.
Given that most trainees will come in with varying degrees of competence, a VR training affords a personalization that is cost-effective to the trainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A different use case was in the context of therapy. 
Drawing inspiration from researchers who currently use VR games in cold settings for patients undergoing burn treatment,
VR affords a setting for paliative care and much more.
We also considered VR for psychological therapy, such as a medium for exposure therapy for anxiety or phobias. 
The cardboard in these cases allows for ease and agency in the patient’s submerging into an alternate reality. 
Moreover, it allows for ease of disposability in the interest of sterilisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a while discussing and envisioning these different use cases, so we did not get the chance to flesh out our personas. 
We did briefly craft a user for the second case.
They are a new hire as a mechanic in a car factory.
While they have experience as a mechanic in a Ford factory, they are new to this Chevy brand. 
They are highly experienced in this field and thus have high technical expertise, but lack the brand-specific knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On Monday as a small group, we discussed personas with respect to Google’s Cardboard VR headset. We approached the task through reverse-engineering, brainstorming different use cases that we knew of or that we could envision. We did generate use cases that were pretty traditional for virtual reality in general, such as video games and sharing of experiences. However, we sought to focus on those that were particularly suited for Google Cardboard.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reading Assignment 3: Formative Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/12/reading3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Assignment 3: Formative Research" /><published>2019-09-12T12:13:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-09-12T12:13:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/12/reading3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/09/12/reading3.html">&lt;p&gt;I first picked the paper by Oulasvirta et al. “Interaction in 4-second Bursts: the Fragmented Nature of Attentional Resource in Mobile HCI.”
It sparked my interest, because I had previously taken a class called “Distraction,” and have since been intrigued with regards to how our modes of attention and distraction are shaped by artefacts around us.
In the paper, Oulasvirta et al. propose a new theoretical framework (i.e. a theoretical contribution to the field) and empirically test the predictive validity of the framework through a field study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their Resource Competition Framework is useful in that it captures the complexity of what competes for a user’s attentional resources in the modern, mobile world.
Moreover, this framework emphasizes the view that the social and cognitive are deeply intertwined,
which helps to advocate for an embodied and situated approach to understanding cognition and the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also picked the paper by Gaver et al. “Design: Cultural probes,” because the word “probe” seemed almost violent, 
like an exploitation of a misunderstood people through extraction and asking for free labour.
However, the packages of maps, postcards, photo albums, and media diaries were endearing. 
Indeed, the “probe” allowed the users to provide candid data on their own time, in a way that was exciting for the participants.
This “non-conventional” method for collecting data is interesting given its affordance of respect for the participant. 
It also allows for a different mode of engagement that is unique to these objects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I first picked the paper by Oulasvirta et al. “Interaction in 4-second Bursts: the Fragmented Nature of Attentional Resource in Mobile HCI.” It sparked my interest, because I had previously taken a class called “Distraction,” and have since been intrigued with regards to how our modes of attention and distraction are shaped by artefacts around us. In the paper, Oulasvirta et al. propose a new theoretical framework (i.e. a theoretical contribution to the field) and empirically test the predictive validity of the framework through a field study.</summary></entry></feed>