<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-31T13:56:08-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">UCD Blog | Isabella Huang</title><subtitle>Blog for CSCI 5839, written by Isabella Huang.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Week 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/08/31/a1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1" /><published>2019-08-31T13:21:48-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-31T13:21:48-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/08/31/a1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/08/31/a1.html">&lt;p&gt;On Monday, we talked about some products that were frustrating to use and some products that were pleasing to use. 
One item that stood out as very frustrating was the bike rack, 
which does not fully account for variations in shape, size, and design of a bicycle, leading to reduced ease of access to lock the bike, reduced manueverability and stability, and potentially damage to the bikes locked at the rack. 
One set of items that stood out as pleasing to use was the suite of Apple products, given that the look and feel of the products are sleek and minimalist in design, as well as their integration with each other (e.g. being able to text from your laptop without having to pick up another device).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, we focused on designing some solutions for problems existing in the Apple TV remote. One of the major problems discovered was that there was no easy way to determine the orientation of the remate.
Thus, our group – consisting of myself, Vinitha, and Jessie – sought out different methods to build assymetries within the remote without sacrificing usability and aesthetic quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One simple idea was the move the buttons down to create a clear divide between the touch area and the buttons. This would reduce the vertical symmetry, but may lead to the buttons being less accessible when the remote is held and navigated by one hand.
Another idea was to simple weight the bottom of the remote. Without changing anything visible to the remote, an added weight would allow the user to feel the correct orientation. 
Other tactile cues were brainstormed, including rubber grips at the back of the remote or a small line dividing the touch pad and button areas on the remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We concluded that any of the proposed ideas would probably suitably address the original problem of determining the orientation of the Apple TV remote, but combining all of them would probably be “overkill” or over-engineering the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On Monday, we talked about some products that were frustrating to use and some products that were pleasing to use. One item that stood out as very frustrating was the bike rack, which does not fully account for variations in shape, size, and design of a bicycle, leading to reduced ease of access to lock the bike, reduced manueverability and stability, and potentially damage to the bikes locked at the rack. One set of items that stood out as pleasing to use was the suite of Apple products, given that the look and feel of the products are sleek and minimalist in design, as well as their integration with each other (e.g. being able to text from your laptop without having to pick up another device).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intro</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/08/27/intro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro" /><published>2019-08-27T23:26:48-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-27T23:26:48-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/08/27/intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2019/08/27/intro.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! My name is Isabella Huang, and I use she/her/hers pronouns. I am a PhD student in Cognitive Science and Computer Science, working with Tammy Sumner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a photo of me scarfing down a semi-frozen burrito after day broke on an alpine start this summer. &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/burrito.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burrito&quot; /&gt;
And another photo of me further along the backpacking loop at Buckskin Pass, ecstatic after meeting Bucky the mountain goat. &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/headshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello! My name is Isabella Huang, and I use she/her/hers pronouns. I am a PhD student in Cognitive Science and Computer Science, working with Tammy Sumner.</summary></entry></feed>